<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Kevin Hendry</title>
  <subtitle>¯_(ツ)_/¯</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.kevinhendry.io/blog</id>
  <link href="http://blog.kevinhendry.io/blog"/>
  <link href="http://blog.kevinhendry.io/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2016-12-28T00:26:03-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Kevin Hendry</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Learning SpriteKit</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.kevinhendry.io/blog/learning-sprite-kit/"/>
    <id>http://blog.kevinhendry.io/blog/learning-sprite-kit/</id>
    <published>2016-12-28T00:26:03-05:00</published>
    <updated>2019-01-01T14:38:07-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin Hendry</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first project I decided to work on is my old game called Zengaku. I’m not really a big fan of game development. It’s just not my calling. I don’t disparage those who love it. I know many do, but it’s not my thing. This is a pretty simple game and I’m able to use the existing code base to help me get started to some degree. But I decided to modernize the code and the UI so that I’d be able to use the latest tools and learn something new  without having to start with nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a number of puzzle files generated and we developed our own simple, but proprietary file format for the game data. I just wanted to be able to extract the data from an example file so I could build and test that my modernized model objects worked correctly and I had a full fleshed out game file. This was simple enough. Although reading some of that old code and its dearth of comments was a bit of a challenge. The file format was meant to be pretty compact and efficient, but not exactly easy to parse or follow. I was able to make it go, but its pretty ugly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m now at the point where I’d like to render the game board layout that I read from the file as images in a scene. Since I want this game to feel more like a game than our previous effort, I chose to use Apple’s 2D rendering framework to make that happen. The old implementation was UIKit based and rather static by most games standards. It was economical for us to build it that way and it seemed like decent trade off since the game itself was really just a number puzzle game with each cell as a data entry field. So what more do you need than some input fields and some buttons. I could probably follow that same path and have my “modern” game out much sooner. Although I still would be rather bored by it and I’d like to make it something that I’d have more fun playing and maybe decide to add a Sudoku and other game modes to at some point if this is popular enough to warrant further development. I don&amp;rsquo;t expect that to be the case. I just don&amp;rsquo;t really want our 1st app to actually completely die.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Beginning Again</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.kevinhendry.io/blog/testing-title/"/>
    <id>http://blog.kevinhendry.io/blog/testing-title/</id>
    <published>2016-11-22T00:53:24-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-07T08:34:16-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin Hendry</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently changed jobs. I was working as an iOS Software Developer at a small firm in my town. I left. I might talk about that a bit more in the future, but not today. Today I’m excited to get my new home on the internet off the ground and to be able to talk about and work on and share some things that I’m doing and going to be doing. I have some aggressive goals for this site and for myself over the next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve made a number of false starts on these ambitious plans in the past and they may yet prove to be another failed attempt. But here I go nonetheless. I plan to create posts here that tell the story of how things are going with my various side projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This build of the site has leaned pretty heavily on the work Ash Furrow has done for his personal site. I thank him a great deal for all the things he&amp;rsquo;s done and shared. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to the side projects. Up first is Zengaku; a number puzzle game similar to Sudoku or Kakuro. A group of 5 co-workers and friends, including me, made an app called Zengaku back in 2009. It was not a financial success. It was a first attempt. But we were still pretty proud of it. It was a success in that we worked together to build it, saw it through to release and iterated on it to try and see if we could make it grow. It didn&amp;rsquo;t, but we did. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no illusions of my re-vamped and modernized build setting the world on fire. But as my first app, and as a passion project I can&amp;rsquo;t stand to see it languish. So I&amp;rsquo;m goign to re-build it with Swift and use Apple&amp;rsquo;s SceneKit APIs to give it a more game like feel than our mostly UIKit based initial implementation. Beyond that I hope that making it free with ads and a simple in-app purchase to remove them will suffice to make it worth my time to keep it going. I may also try a macOS port if the re-launched iOS version does decently.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
